<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-09T20:11:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Burned-over District</title><subtitle>Thinking about the theological sciences.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Doing Theology with the Reformers (by Gerald Bray)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/22/doing-theology-with-the-reformers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Doing Theology with the Reformers (by Gerald Bray)" /><published>2020-04-22T20:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-22T20:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/22/doing-theology-with-the-reformers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/22/doing-theology-with-the-reformers.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing Theology with the Reformers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Gerald Bray&lt;br /&gt;
InterVarsity Press, 2019&lt;br /&gt;
ISBN 978-0-8308-6583-3 (digital)&lt;br /&gt;
ISBN 978-0-8308-5251-2 (print)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this book Gerald Bray provides an introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“to the world in which the
Reformation took place, to the mindset of those who led it and gave it direction,
and to the way in which the initial burst of spiritual energy and enthusiasm was
gradually codified into the confessional statements that now form the basis of
denominational identities in the Protestant world” (Preface, page VII).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bray wrote the book to provide background information for the
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reformation Commentary on Scriptures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; series. But the book stands on its
own as an introduction to the theology and hermeneutics of the Reformers. We are
able to enter into the mindset of several Reformers: Bucer, Calvin,
Cranmer, Knox, Luther, Melanchthon, Tyndale, Zwingli, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Books" /><category term="Bray, Gerald" /><category term="Hermeneutics" /><category term="The Reformation" /><category term="Theological Sciences" /><summary type="html">Doing Theology with the Reformers Gerald Bray InterVarsity Press, 2019 ISBN 978-0-8308-6583-3 (digital) ISBN 978-0-8308-5251-2 (print)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The C. S. Lewis Book Ratio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/c-s-lewis-book-ratio.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The C. S. Lewis Book Ratio" /><published>2019-10-17T16:56:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-17T16:56:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/c-s-lewis-book-ratio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/c-s-lewis-book-ratio.html">&lt;p&gt;C. S. Lewis recommended old books. By “old” he meant books that had been written centuries ago. He discussed his rule on reading new and old books in his introduction to &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the Incarnation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Saint Athanasius [GLH Publishing Reprint, 2018].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is a good rule, after reading a new book, never to allow yourself another new one till you have read an old one in between. If that is too much for you, you should at least read on old one to every three new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Lewis’s way of thinking the old books have been tested. They are much safer for the “amateur”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A new book is still on its trial and the amateur is not in a position to judge it. It has to be tested against the great body of Christian thought down the ages, and all its hidden implications (often unsuspected by the author himself) have to be brought to light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lewis wanted his students to read the primary sources rather than the secondary literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The simplest student will be able to understand, if not all, yet a very great deal of what Plato said [in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symposium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, translated into English]; but hardly anyone can understand some modern books on Platonism. It has always therefore been one my main endeavours as a teacher to persuade the young that first-hand knowledge is not only more worth acquiring than second-hand knowledge, but is usually much easier and more delightful to acquire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I myself read numerous old books and I also read numerous new books about the past. In my opinion we have not reached a new height in the theological sciences recently. It seems quite possible that we have past the maxima some centuries ago. I think the sixteenth, seventeenth, and
eighteenth centuries reach several high water marks in theology. But even if I am wrong about those high water marks we should still focus on the older books since they have stood the test of time and they show us where many ideas really came from.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Lewis, C S" /><summary type="html">C. S. Lewis recommended old books. By “old” he meant books that had been written centuries ago. He discussed his rule on reading new and old books in his introduction to On the Incarnation by Saint Athanasius [GLH Publishing Reprint, 2018].</summary></entry></feed>